bobsled.com 2013-09-02

# Bobsled™ by T-Mobile

T-Mobile USA, Inc. (“T-Mobile”) is committed to protecting the privacy and security of your personal information. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) applies solely to the various “Bobsled”-branded services (“Services”) and software applications (“Software”), the Bobsled website at bobsled.com (the “Site”), the content and materials made available to you on or through the Services, Software or Site (“Bobsled Content”) (the Software, Services, Site and Bobsled Content are referred to herein collectively as “Bobsled”) and your activities in connection with Bobsled. This Policy describes the personal information we may collect about you, how we may use it, when we may disclose it, how we safeguard it, and how you may access it and control its use in connection with T-Mobile’s marketing communications. The policy also provides other important privacy information and describes when and how T-Mobile may change this policy and how to contact T-Mobile with any questions or comments.

COLLECTION, USE, DISCLOSURE, AND SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION.

Personal Information

This policy applies to personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”), which is information that can be directly associated with a specific person or entity. Personal Information includes, but is not limited to, your name, email address, home address, mobile phone number, contacts and certain information, including login credentials, related to your social networks and other third party sites. Personal Information does not include “anonymous” or “aggregate” information – neither of which are associated with a specific person or entity. When you register with Bobsled or when you choose to add information to your profile, we will ask you for Personal Information. This refers to information about you that can be used to contact or identify you.

Collection of Personal Information

Voice Services

In order to access certain features of Bobsled, you must register to create an account (“Account”). Your Account for voice Services uses your social media identity as your identity within the voice Services. The voice Services will automatically load the contacts from the social media websites you attach to your Bobsled Account. This feature cannot be turned off. If you do not want your contacts from a social media site uploaded, you should not attach that social media site to your Bobsled Account.

Messaging Services

In order to use messaging Services, you will be required to provide certain information to create a Profile and you will establish a username and a password. The messaging Services will automatically upload contact information from your phone for use with Bobsled. This feature cannot be turned off. If you do not want your contacts uploaded, you must not install this Software. Once you are a registered user, you can invite friends to join Bobsled by sending invitation emails via T-Mobile’s automated invitation system.

While the Messaging Services offer you the ability to determine how much information you wish to share with Bobsled though your “Account Settings,” any Personal Information or other content that you voluntarily disclose online (for example, on your public Bobsled profile, in posts, comments, or notes) becomes publicly available and could be collected and used by others. Your phone number, account User Name, or your full name if you choose to provide it within your Account Settings, is displayed to other users when you post, send direct messages, or comment. Other users may also search Bobsled and find your public profile, which will include your User Name and any post made to everyone or in “public mode.” Likewise, comments that you submit to the Site may be redistributed through the Internet and other media, and could be viewed and/or used by the general public. In addition, if you chose to connect Bobsled to your other networks (including, but not limited to Facebook and Twitter), any information you post and your User Name through Bobsled will be shared with your other networks.

Information automatically collected

T-Mobile automatically collects certain information, some of which may be associated with Personal Information, whenever you use Bobsled. For example, the Bobsled systems capture details about the type and location of wireless device(s) you use, calls and SMS you send and receive, and other services you use. When your computer Web browser or other communication device accesses the Site or uses the Services, T-Mobile automatically receives certain information, such as your IP address, browser type, date and time, and the Web page you visited before visiting the Site.

Use of Personal Information

T-Mobile uses Personal Information for a variety of business purposes, including for example, to respond to your requests for Services or assistance; anticipate and resolve actual and potential problems with the Site, Software or Services; create and improve the Site, Software or Services; make internal business decisions about current and future offers; provide personalized Services and user experiences; and protect T-Mobile’s rights and property.

Marketing Communications

T-Mobile and its Bobsled Service Providers (as defined below) may also use your Personal Information to contact you (via such means as SMS, email, etc.) with Bobsled marketing or promotional materials. If you do not want to receive marketing communications from T-Mobile or its Bobsled partners in connection with Bobsled, you must complete the form at the following link: <http://www.t-mobile.com/company/website/OptOut.aspx>.

Alerts and Notifications

“Alerts” or “Notifications” are messages that you elect to receive and other information that may be of interest to you (such as, when a friend is nearby or your favorite team’s final score in a recent game). You receive these alerts and other notifications at your discretion and as determined by you in your messaging Account Settings. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive these communications from Bobsled please update your “Account Settings” page (part of the Messaging Services) or follow the unsubscribe instructions that may be provided in the communications.

Targeted Advertising

Some of Bobsled is supported by advertising revenue and the Service may display advertisements and promotions. These advertisements may be targeted to you based on the content of information stored on Bobsled, or other information that Bobsled or T-Mobile may have about you. You cannot opt out of receiving targeted advertising while using Bobsled.

Not all marketing communications you receive on your device are sent or authorized by T-Mobile or its Bobsled Service Providers. When you provide your mobile number or other contact information to others, you may receive unwanted calls, SMS, or e-mails on your device. T-Mobile takes steps to reduce unsolicited advertising, but T-Mobile cannot block all such advertisements or unwanted communications.

Disclosure of Personal Information.

T-Mobile will not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your Personal Information to unaffiliated third-parties to market their services or products to you, except as described by this Policy, unless T-Mobile obtains your prior consent to do so. T-Mobile may disclose your Personal Information to unaffiliated third-parties as follows:

Registered Users

When you register through the Site and submit your Personal Information to create a profile page, other Users will see your “User Name.” You can choose what other Personal Information you provide as part of your profile, including but not limited to your phone number, location and information contained in your posts (“Other User Information”). Providing Other User Information is voluntary and should correlate with the degree of interaction you want to have with other Users. Should you choose to disclose your information to “everyone” based on the settings in your post or profile, any location information that you choose to share will become public.

Aggregate Information

T-Mobile may share aggregated information in a form that does not identify you personally with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling and to deliver targeted advertising about other products and services.

Service Providers

T-Mobile may employ third party companies to facilitate Bobsled, to provide Bobsled on T-Mobile’s behalf (for example and without limitation, the “Service Providers”) to perform Site-related services (for example and without limitation, maintenance services, database management, web analytics and improvement of the Site’s features) or to assist T-Mobile in analyzing how Bobsled is used. Currently, Bobsled is provided and operated by T-Mobile’s third party partners Vivox, Inc. (“Vivox”) and HDmessaging, Inc. (“HDmessaging”). Vivox, HDmessaging and T-Mobile’s other third party suppliers of services related to Bobsled are collectively referred to herein as “Service Providers.” Service Providers have access to your Personal Information in order to provide specific Services on T-Mobile’s behalf as dictated by T-Mobile, and may not to disclose or use it for any purpose inconsistent with this Policy. Service Providers may not use or disclose your Personal Information for any purpose other than to deliver the Services described herein without your separate and prior consent. Whenever any of these Service Providers cease providing the Bobsled Service, or any specific Services related thereto, to a customer following account deletion pursuant to the account deletion process identified in the FAQ (http://www.bobsled.com/#!/faq) they will delete and expunge the Personal Information that they have collected, stored, or generated about you within 48 hours of the time they cease providing the Bobsled Service or any specific Services related thereto.

Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement

T-Mobile may disclose personal information or communications where T-Mobile believes in good faith such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law or respond to legal process (for example, lawful subpoena, court order, E-9-1-1 information); to enforce or apply agreements; to protect T-Mobile’s rights or property; in connection with claims, disputes, or litigation; to protect users of T-Mobile’s services and other carriers or providers from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of, or subscription to, such services; or if T-Mobile determines disclosure is necessary in an emergency situation.

Business Transfers

T-Mobile may disclose personal information as part of a corporate business transaction, such as a merger or acquisition, joint venture, corporate reorganization, financing, or sale of company assets, or in the unlikely event of insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership, in which personal information could be transferred to third-parties as a business asset in the transaction.

Security and Retention of Personal Information

T-Mobile uses a variety of physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect Personal Information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure while it is under T-Mobile’s control. Although T-Mobile cannot guarantee that loss, misuse, or alteration of your Personal Information will not occur, T-Mobile strives to prevent such occurrences.

T-Mobile retains Personal Information for as long as T-Mobile has a business need or as applicable laws, regulations, or government orders require. When T-Mobile disposes of Personal Information, T-Mobile uses reasonable procedures to erase or render it unreadable (for example, shredding documents and wiping electronic media). T-Mobile will make reasonable attempts to notify you if T-Mobile determines that a security breach involving your Personal Information has occurred that T-Mobile reasonably believes creates a risk of identity theft or Services disruption, or as otherwise required by law.

Changing or Deleting Your Information

Voice Services

The policies and procedures of each social network site that you attach to the Bobsled Voice Services define how to change the information they pass to T-Mobile or its Service Providers. In order to change or stop the flow of information passed to the Voice Services, you must consult and follow the policies and procedures of that social network site. For example, if you have authorized one or more Bobsled Facebook applications to access your Facebook account information, you must edit the application settings, or deauthorize the application(s) on Facebook in order to change the information that is provided to the Bobsled Service by the application(s).

Messaging Services

You can review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in your registration profile by accessing your Account Settings (Profile) in your Account at the Site. If you completely delete all your Personal Information, your Account will be deactivated.

OTHER PRIVACY INFORMATION.

Children

Bobsled, including the Site and Services, is not designed for children under the age of 13 and T-Mobile does not intentionally or knowingly collect Personal Information on the Site from anyone under the age of 13. T-Mobile encourages parents to be involved in the online activities of their children to ensure that no information is collected from a child without parental permission.

Cookies

Like many websites, T-Mobile uses “cookies” to collect information. A cookie is a small data file transferred to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. T-Mobile uses cookies for two purposes. First, T-Mobile utilizes persistent cookies to save your registration ID and login password for future logins to the Site. Second, T-Mobile utilizes session ID cookies to enable certain features of the Site, to better understand how you interact with the Site and to monitor usage by visitors and web traffic routing on the Site. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from the Site and Services and then close your browser. Third party advertisers on the Site may also place or read cookies on your browser. You may be able to instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site or all functionality of the Service.

Third-Party Advertising.

You may see third-party advertisements on the Site or the Software or while using the Services. These third-party advertisers, or their ad networks, may place or access cookies on your device or computer and may collect certain anonymous information about your visit on the Site. The third-party advertisers who provide these ads may use this information to provide you with advertising on the Site, as well as on other sites. This advertising may be tailored to the interests the advertisers have inferred from your browsing of the Site or other Web sites with which the third-party is affiliated as an ad server or ad network. T-Mobile does not provide Personal Information about you directly to the advertiser. T-Mobile may, however, provide third-party advertisers with anonymous demographic or similar data (unrelated to your browsing activities) that does not personally identify you. This data may be used by them to help tailor their ads on the Site, and on other sites.

Third-party advertisers or ad networks operating on the Site are required to participate in the opt-out process established by the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI). To learn more, or to opt-out of the automatic collection of information by these parties, please visit the NAI site (http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). Please note that this opt-out is cookie-based. If you change computers, change Web browsers, or delete cookies, you will need to visit the NAI site and opt-out again. T-Mobile does not have control over or access to any information contained in the cookies that are set on your computer by ad servers, ad networks, or third-party advertisers.

Links to Other Sites

Bobsled contains links to, and may allow you to visit, other websites (“Third Party Sites”). If you choose to visit any of these Third Party Sites by “clicking on” another third party link or navigating to a Third Party Site, you will be directed to that third party’s website. The fact that T-Mobile links to a website or presents a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of T-Mobile’s affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. T-Mobile does not exercise control over Third Party Websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit Personal Information from you. Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the Personal Information you submit to them. T-Mobile encourages you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

Other Governing Terms

This policy does not modify or alter any applicable agreement you have with T-Mobile. For example, the Bobsled Terms of Use and Acceptable Use Policy govern your use of Bobsled only. If you use other T-Mobile products or services, the T-Mobile Terms and Conditions, one or more applicable service agreements, and certain other terms may apply to your use, purchase, or subscription. If this policy conflicts with any portion of those terms and agreements, those terms and agreements govern to the extent of the inconsistency.

Protecting Your Own Personal Information

You play an important role in ensuring the security of Personal Information, including protecting against unauthorized access to your device or your online account. T-Mobile encourages you to use passwords to prevent unauthorized access to your device, your online account, and your voicemail. T-Mobile recommends that you use unique, non-obvious passwords, that you periodically change your passwords, and that you not share your passwords with others. Notify T-Mobile immediately if you believe your Personal Information has been accessed without your consent.

International Transfer

Bobsled stores all your Personal Information in the United States. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to T-Mobile, Bobsled transfers Personal Information to the United States and processes it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Voice Services

You may use the Voice Services to call social network contacts located anywhere, or to call phone numbers located in the United States, Puerto Rico, and Canada only.

Messaging Services

You must have a mobile phone number to use the Messaging Services. You can send messages to your social network contacts located anywhere in the world, or to mobile phone numbers located in the United States, Puerto Rico, and Canada only.

POLICY UPDATES AND CONTACT INFORMATION.

Changes to This Policy

T-Mobile may update this policy if T-Mobile materially changes its practices or if legal or regulatory changes require it. If T-Mobile decides to use or disclose Personal Information in a way that is materially different from that which was stated in this policy at the time the Personal Information was collected, T-Mobile will notify you by posting notice of the change on the Site’s home page for at least 30 days before T-Mobile implements that change. You agree that the express acceptance by you, or your continued use of the Bobsled Services after the 30-day notice period, constitutes your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy. You should refer to this policy often for the latest information and the effective date of any changes.

How to Contact T-Mobile

If you have any questions or comments about this policy or about Bobsled by T-Mobile’s privacy practices, send an e-mail message to bobsled_privacy@t-mobile.com. You may also direct your privacy- related comments or questions to the address below:

Bobsled by T-Mobile   
T-Mobile USA Inc.  
Attn: Chief Privacy Officer   
12920 SE 38th Street   
Bellevue, Washington 98006
